# Luke Belliveau

Software Engineer

Boston, USA linkedin.com/in/lukebelliveau github.com/lukebelliveau hi@lukebelliveau.dev 603-320-9505

Luke is a software delivery consultant with 7 years of experience engineering full stack web applications and services at enterprise scale. If you need to get an application built or some code untangled, there's a good chance he can help.

Skills

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Python, Golang, C#

Deploy, Automation, Hosting

AWS, Digital Ocean, Firebase, Jenkins, Spinnaker, GitHub Actions, Vercel

Frameworks & Build Tooling React, Next.js, Redux, Vite, Konva, Highcharts

Testing Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Vitest, Cypress,

Jest, JUnit, Chai / Mocha, Selenium

**Work Experience** 

Technical Partner ZUUT.co 2022 - Current

Luke collaborated with ZUUT's founder, working from the product's inception all the way through a successful launch. Handling all facets of development, he:

- Built a full-fledged interactive computer aided design web application, enabling users to save, share and collaborate in real time on gardening plots featuring a deep interaction & collision detection engine
- Designed and implemented an account and data management system using Firebase services such as Authentication, Realtime DB, and Cloud Storage
- Implemented system & interface for users to compare, contrast, and purchase equipment for their grow designs featuring an affiliate link system using Amazon's APIs, successfully qualifying ZUUT for Amazon's Associates Program
- Integrated content management systems enabling nontechnical users to update item metadata and create blog content with a simple interface, using Airtable and Contentful
- Hired & managed a team of freelance developers & designers to accelerate development

## Software Delivery Consultant N

**NuWave Technologies** 

2021 - Current

Luke managed the development and maintenance of NuWave's suite of web applications. With NuWave, he:

- · Managed development of the Prizm API Gateway management console from inception to post-launch
- Engineered a successful migration from AngularJS to React for NuWave's LightWave Client and Server products
- Created new automated testing pipelines and ran workshops and training, facilitated a culture of testing and continuous integration
- Played an instrumental role in the interview, evaluation & mentorship of new hires

## Senior Cloud Infra Engineer Grubhub

2018 - 2020

On Grubhub's Cloud Infrastructure team, Luke designed & implemented frameworks, tools, and services that enabled web, mobile, and site reliability engineers to do their jobs as efficiently as they can. In his time at GrubHub, he:

- Engineered changes to core framework to facilitate communication between microservices in a new Envoy service mesh architecture
- Led integration of SMS service with a new provider, handling the development, evaluation, and communication with stakeholders on both ends
- Ownership of Notifications stack of microservices in Java (with Guice and Spring), spanning SMS, mobile push, email, and fax functionalities
- Built a service in React & Python used by Site Reliability Engineers to view system status and make changes during outages
- Designed the architecture & database schemas for a new notifications platform. This service was used by product and marketing teams at GrubHub to manage notifications for email, SMS, push, and fax.

As a Senior Engineer at ThoughtWorks, Luke worked on software delivery teams for clients in e-commerce and cybersecurity. In this role, Luke:

- Built a dashboard for analysts to monitor web traffic with rich interactions and data visualizations, built with Vue & Highcharts
- Facilitated front-end training sessions for the company, coordinating speakers and workshops for bimonthly meetups in a global community of React and Vue developers
- Designed APIs and data pipelines to facilitate a seamless integration of Kroger's e-commerce platform with a newly acquired subsidiary
- Worked with designers and executive stakeholders to determine key features/specifications and break them into manageable tasks
- Developed a backend-for-frontend in Golang to aggregate, analyze and perform transformations on a large breadth of logs before serving them to the client, improving performance

## Associate Software Engineer ThoughtWorks

2016 - 2017

Luke began his career as an Associate Software Engineer at ThoughtWorks, where he was deployed on a software delivery team at one of the largest health insurance firms in the United States. In this role, his achievements include:

- Delivering a full-stack application in JavaScript+React and Java, serving as the interface for users to apply for coverage and request changes
- Serving as a front-end specialist, participating in architecture meetings and facilitating weekly discussions about React and JavaScript topics
- · Mentoring new hires, providing weekly office hours and coaching sessions

## **Freelance Projects**

## https://selenium.dev

2019

Given a set of mockups, I delivered a speedy static website for Selenium, a popular browser automation tool. Built with Jekyll and Hugo.

Devil's Dice Game 2018

I was hired to build this exciting party game in 2018, where users place a phone on the table and face various challenges based on the roll of the dice. This app has a special place in my heart - a year after its release, I was staying at a hostel in Slovakia, and I noticed a group of people playing the game in the kitchen! It remains active today, and enjoys a 4.5 star rating on the Google Play Store with over 10,000 downloads.

#### SATURATION - BROCKHAMPTON

2017

Official application for world-famous boyband BROCKHAMPTON, designed to release music videos and other exclusive goodies before their general release to external platforms. With over 10,000 downloads, SATURATION enjoyed a rating of 5 stars on the Google Play store, where it was active from 2017–2019.

#### Education -

**Bachelors Computer Science** 

University of Connecticut

2011 - 2016